http://www.potsdam.edu/privacy-policy

Instagram
Combined Shape
quotation
Created with Sketch.
Privacy Protection
At SUNY Potsdam, we are committed both to protecting individuals' privacy and to allowing individuals and businesses to interact more easily with SUNY Potsdam. We recognize that visitors must be confident that their privacy is protected when they visit an official SUNY Potsdam website. Visitors can travel through most of an official SUNY Potsdam website without offering any information about themselves. Sometimes SUNY Potsdam does need information to provide services, often at the request of visitors, and this policy explains our online information practices.
SUNY Potsdam does not collect any personal information about visitors unless they provide that information voluntarily by sending an email, completing one of several online forms, or completing an online transaction.
This policy is consistent with the provisions of the NYS Internet Security and Privacy Act, the Freedom of Information Law, and the Personal Privacy Protection Law.
Information Collected Automatically When You Visit an Official SUNY Potsdam Website
When you visit an official SUNY Potsdam website, SUNY Potsdam automatically collects and stores the following information about your visit:
The Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computer that accessed our website
The type of browser, its version and the operating system on which that browser is running
The web page from which the user's computer accessed the current web page and the web page at which the user entered an official SUNY Potsdam website
The date and time of the user's request
The pages that were visited and the amount of time spent at an official SUNY Potsdam website
The size of the content, in bytes, of any file or document sent to the user's computer
The country where your computer resides
Search engines that brought users to an official SUNY Potsdam web site and the text search strings that allowed users to find an official SUNY Potsdam website
Downloads the user requested (e.g., .pdf and .mov files) from an official SUNY Potsdam website
None of the above-mentioned information is deemed to constitute personal information by the NYS Internet Privacy and Security Act. The information that is collected automatically is used to improve the content of official SUNY Potsdam websites and to help SUNY Potsdam understand how users are interacting with its web sites. This information is collected for statistical analysis and to determine what information is of most and least interest to our users. The information is not collected for commercial marketing purposes and SUNY Potsdam does not sell or otherwise disclose the information collected from an official SUNY Potsdam web site for commercial marketing purposes.
Information Collected When You Email an Official SUNY Potsdam Website or Complete a Transaction
During your visit to an official SUNY Potsdam website, you may send an email to SUNY Potsdam. Your e-mail address and the contents of your message will be collected. The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats attached to or included in the message. Your email address and the information included in your message will be used to respond to you, to address issues you identify, to improve this web site, or to forward your message to another SUNY Potsdam employee for appropriate action. Your e-mail address is not collected for commercial purposes and SUNY Potsdam does not sell or otherwise disclose your e-mail address for commercial purposes.
During your visit to an official SUNY Potsdam website, you may complete a transaction such as a request to establish an internship, an update of your alumni information, or a gift to the College. The information collected by SUNY Potsdam, including personal information volunteered by you in completing the transaction, is used by SUNY Potsdam to operate our programs and may be disclosed by SUNY Potsdam for those purposes that may be reasonably ascertained from the nature and terms of the transaction in which the information was submitted.
SUNY Potsdam does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 14 or create profiles of children under the age of 14. Users are cautioned, however, that the collection of personal information submitted in an email will be treated as though it were submitted by an adult, and may, unless exempted from access by federal or State law, be subject to public access. We encourage parents and adult family to be involved in children's Internet activities and to provide guidance whenever children are asked to provide personal information online.
Disclosure of Information Collected through an Official SUNY Potsdam Website
The collection of information through an official SUNY Potsdam website and the disclosure of that information are subject to the provisions of the NYS Internet Security and Privacy Act. Only if you have consented to the collection or disclosure of personal information will SUNY Potsdam collect your personal information through an official SUNY Potsdam website or disclose your personal information collected through an official SUNY Potsdam website. Your voluntary disclosure of personal information to SUNY Potsdam constitutes consent to the collection and disclosure of the information by SUNY Potsdam for the purposes for which you disclosed the information to SUNY Potsdam.
However, SUNY Potsdam may collect or disclose personal information without consent if the collection or disclosure is: (1) necessary to perform the statutory duties of SUNY Potsdam, or necessary for SUNY Potsdam to operate a program authorized by law, or authorized by state or federal statute or regulation; (2) made pursuant to a court order or by law; (3) for the purpose of validating the identity of the user; or (4) of information to be used solely for statistical purposes that is in a form that cannot be used to identify any particular person.
Further, the disclosure of information, including personal information, collected through an official SUNY Potsdam website is subject to the provisions of the Freedom of Information Law and the Personal Privacy Protection Law.
SUNY Potsdam may disclose personal information to federal or state law enforcement authorities to enforce its rights against unauthorized access or attempted unauthorized access to SUNY Potsdam's information technology assets.
Retention of Information Collected through an Official SUNY Potsdam Website
The information collected through an official SUNY Potsdam website is retained by SUNY Potsdam in accordance with the records retention and disposition requirements of the New York State Arts & Cultural Affairs Law. Information concerning these records retention and disposition schedules may be obtained through the Internet privacy policy contact listed in this policy.
Access to and Correction of Personal Information Collected through an Official SUNY Potsdam Website
Any user may submit a request to SUNY Potsdam's privacy compliance officer to determine whether personal information pertaining to that user has been collected through an official SUNY Potsdam website. Any such request shall be made in writing and must be accompanied by reasonable proof of identity of the user. Reasonable proof of identity may include verification of a signature, inclusion of an identifier generally known only to the user, or similar appropriate identification. The address of the privacy compliance officer is:
Privacy Compliance Officer
SUNY Potsdam
Office of College Communications
44 Pierrepont Ave.
Raymond Hall 604
Potsdam, New York 13676
The privacy compliance officer shall, within five (5) business days of the receipt of a proper request, provide access to the personal information; deny access in writing, explaining the reasons therefore; or acknowledge the receipt of the request in writing, stating the approximate date when the request will be granted or denied, which date shall not be more than thirty (30) days from the date of the acknowledgment.
In the event that SUNY Potsdam has collected personal information pertaining to a user through an official SUNY Potsdam website and that information is to be provided to the user pursuant to the user's request, the privacy compliance officer shall inform the user of his or her right to request that the personal information be amended or corrected under the procedures set forth in section 95 of the Public Officers Law.
Confidentiality and Integrity of Personal Information Collected through an Official SUNY Potsdam Website
SUNY Potsdam is strongly committed to protecting personal information collected through an official SUNY Potsdam website against unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Consequently, SUNY Potsdam limits employee access to personal information collected through an official SUNY Potsdam website to only those employees who need access to the information in the performance of their official duties. Employees who have access to this information follow appropriate procedures in connection with any disclosures of personal information.
In addition, SUNY Potsdam has implemented procedures to safeguard the integrity of its information technology assets, including, but not limited to, authentication, authorization, monitoring, auditing, and encryption. These security procedures have been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day operations of official SUNY Potsdam websites as part of our continuing commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the electronic transmission of information.
For website security purposes and to maintain the availability of official SUNY Potsdam websites for all users, SUNY Potsdam employs software to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise damage an official SUNY Potsdam website.
Disclaimer
The information provided in this privacy policy should not be construed as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof the security of information provided through an official SUNY Potsdam website.
Contact Information
For questions regarding this Internet privacy policy, please contact the SUNY Potsdam privacy compliance officer via email at communications@potsdam.edu or by regular mail at:
Privacy Compliance Officer
SUNY Potsdam
Office of College Communications
44 Pierrepont Ave.
Raymond Hall 604
Potsdam, New York 13676
Definitions
The following definitions apply to this policy:
Personal information: For purposes of this policy, "personal information" means any information concerning a natural person which, because of name, number, symbol, mark, or other identifier, can be used to identify that natural person.
User: shall have the meaning set forth in subdivision 8 of section 202 of the State Technology Law.
An official SUNY Potsdam website: For purposes of this policy, "an official SUNY Potsdam website" means a website that serves an external audience beyond SUNY Potsdam faculty, staff, and current students, that is, www.potsdam.edu and the inquiry forms on this page: www.potsdam.edu/admissions/request_info. Depending on SUNY Potsdam website development and growth, this definition is subject to change at any time. To learn exactly which domains are official SUNY Potsdam websites at this time, contact the Privacy Compliance Officer at the address listed above.
